<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SDS 348 Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SDS 348 Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SDS 348 Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Taylor Wolfenberger (tw25848)  Introduction The two datasets I have chosen describe various natality measures and infant mortality rates for two races, namely, black and white. The two datasets converge from the years 1960-2012. The first dataset, ‘BWNatality’, consists of the variables “Year”, “Race”, “Live Births”, “Birth Rate”, and “Fertility Rate”. Fertility rate is defined as the number of births per 1000 women of reproductive age (15-44), and birth rate is the number of live births per 1000 women in the total population per year (without taking particular age groups into account) (Source: 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDS 348 Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Taylor Wolfenberger (tw25848)  Introduction For this project, I have chosen to utilize the merged dataset that I created in Project 1. The dataset describes various natality measures and infant mortality rates for two races, namely, black and white. The variables in the dataset include “Year”, “Race”, “Live Births”, “Birth Rate”, “Fertility Rate”, and “Infant Mortality Rate.” The “Year” variable ranges from 1960-2012; these were the years over which the data was collected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Python and R Together</title>
      <link>/blog/pythonpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/pythonpost/</guid>
      <description>Using Python and R Together In this post, I will demonstrate the ways in which Python and R can be used communicate with each other. More specifically, I will take you on a journey to an alternate dimension in which people speak their thoughts aloud.
Do you ever wish that you could hear other peoples’ thoughts? Whether you are on a first date or interviewing for a job, at times it would prove useful to know what another person is thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>